I pushed harder to solve a customer problem,
and ended up making collaboration harder.
I was asking sibling teams to commit capacity.
Their leaders were already stretched,
and I kept pushing before I really understood their priorities.
We focus on our own problems.
We know all the details, so they feel bigger and more urgent.
But we don't have the same visibility into other teams' problems.
They can seem less important, simply because we know less about them.
As we become more senior, we need to make an extra effort
to understand those other perspectives.
So before pushing for commitment, ask:
Can we understand the problems we are trying to solve,
and work out what matters most for the organization?